J. Jared Watson

PHONE 512 721 8658

EMAIL jjaredwatson@gmail.com

WEBSITE jjaredwatson.com



EXPERIENCE

Picnik / Austin, TX / 2017 - Present

General Manager, Graphic Designer

I led and managed a team of over 50 employees, and helped to decrease the labor budget by 5%, while I also oversaw a year in which we increased business by 20%. I modernized and organized administrative processes for efficiency, readability, and speed. I helped cultivate a strong and positive culture, and reduced staff turnover by focusing on employee growth and cross-training.

Freelance Technical Writer / 2017 - Present

Technical Writer

I drafted and designed multiple resumes with a 100% resulting in jobs. I crafted various types of letters and e-mails to customers. I created various instructions and documentation for use by coworkers and employees.

Progressive Insurance / Austin, TX / 2016

Commercial Lines Service Specialist

I advised agents and customers on commercial insurance policies, and authored and expedited specialized documents, like state and federal filings, which decreased the amount of time customer's were out of compliance with local and national Department of Transportation requirements, thereby saving them time and money.

Olivia / Austin, TX / 2013 - 2016

General Manager, Assistant Manager, Bar Tender

I overhauled our cocktail program and reduced waste by using fresh juices, making our own mixes from scratch, and by focusing on classic craft cocktails, while achieving the lowest liquor costs in years. I coordinated multiple large budget private events and oversaw their success.

PROFILE

I am a highly adaptable and dedicated communication expert. I enjoy collaborating with teams to produce meaningful work in an environment that encourages continual growth. I contribute written, organizational, and customer service skills that compliment any company.

SKILLS

Microsoft Office Suite
Google Suite
Adobe Suite
HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
Affinity Designer
Sketch

Intermediate Spanish, spoken and written

EDUCATION

University of Memphis
B.A. in English
Studied persuasive and creative writing, and literary criticism.